Yousef Suleiman

708-541-0259 | yousefsuleiman10@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/yousef-suleiman-4ba75a242 yojoecapital.github.io/portfolio

SUMMARY

Passionate and hardworking graduate student with 2 years of internship experience in business technology. Proficient in a wide range of programming languages and frameworks, with a solid background in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence. Currently seeking a role in full stack web development with a company that values collaboration and creativity.

EDUCATION

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL

MAY 2024

Master of Applied Science, Artificial Intelligence, GPA 3.89 Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, GPA 3.90

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C#, C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, T-SQL, SQLite
- Frameworks & Libraries: .NET, .NET Core, React, SvelteKit, Entity Framework, Prisma
- Machine Learning: TensorFlow, PyTorch
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Tailwind CSS
- Development Tools: Linux, Git, Unity
 Design Tools: LaTeX, Blender, Moho

WORK EXPERIENCE

Development Operations Intern

DataServ, St. Louis, MO

JUN 2023 - present

- Collaborated with DevOps team to integrate customized data-load solutions for over 100 unique clients, leveraging backend development skills, utilizing shell scripts, and job scheduling.
- Optimized T-SQL database operations by consolidating tables with multiple triggers into a singular, more concise trigger, leading to significant performance improvements.
- Standardized and migrated data-load and import workflows for 12 different client solutions from Tidal to JAMS job scheduler.

Business Technology Intern

IAA, Westchester, IL

DEC 2022 - FEB 2023

JUN 2022 - JUL 2022

- Created a REST API for efficiently populating internal client metric reports using ASP.NET MVC, C#, and T-SQL.
- Conducted QA testing for business rule engine implementation on vehicle title and registration forms, ensuring accuracy and compliance with company standards.
- Led a team of 2 other interns in scripting and delivering voice lines for a marketing animation presented during a meeting with executives and fellow interns.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Quran Dojo (Web Application)

SEP 2022 - present

- Designing and developing a web application to enhance Quranic studies for students and teachers.
- Initiated project using ASP.NET and Entity Framework then later transitioned to SvelteKit and Prisma for improved user experience and financially viable hosting options.
- Intending to enrich Quranic studies by implementing the application in various Quran institutes, beginning with Mosque Foundation Education Center.

Jen (Multiplayer Turn-Based Game)

- DEC 2022 JUN 2023
- Built a multiplayer turn-based video game focusing on strategy and player collaboration.
- Modeled game entities with Blender and programmed in C# under Unity's game engine.
- Planning to publish 'Jen' on Steam.

PokeScanner (Image Classifier)

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

- Engaged in a team of 6 students to design a Pokemon image classifier web application in React.
- Managed training and fine tuning of a Convolutional Neural Network model with TensorFlow.
- Presented the project during Innovation Day at Illinois Tech, demonstrating application use cases as a videogame companion and TV show guide.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Quran Teacher AUG 2018 - present

Mosque Foundation Education Center, Bridgeview, IL

- Guiding students in Quranic studies, providing personalized assistance tailored to ages ranging from 13 to 18.
- Facilitated pronunciation and comprehension of Arabic text through reading exercises and class discussions.
- Fostered a supportive learning environment by encouraging collaboration and camaraderie.

HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Dean's List, Illinois Tech
 Early acceptance to Accelerated Master's Program, Illinois Tech
 MAR 2020

Valedictorian, Universal High School
 MAY 2020